Cover Letter

hellwagner.io martin.hellwagner@gmail.com +43 670 604 2089

Company Person

Linz, 01.01.2022

To Whom It May Concern,

my name is Martin Hellwagner, and I'm an experienced Full Stack Web Developer as well as DevOps Engineer hailing from Linz. I'd like to take this opportunity to introduce myself and argue why I believe I'm a great addition to the Marketing team at Dynatrace.

Since my childhood, I was fascinated by computers, the Internet and the sheer endless opportunities in the realm of these technologies. That's why it may come as no surprise that following my high school graduation, I enrolled in the Bachelor's degree in Computer Science at the Johannes Kepler University (JKU) in Linz. After passing these studies with distinction in 2013, I moved to Berlin to enroll in a Master's degree in Audio Communication and Technology at the Technical University (TU), which I completed with honors in 2016.

Thereafter, I started my first full-time employment in a startup focusing on Music Technology. That's where I got in contact with my first Hyperscaler (Google Cloud Platform), with me being in charge of monitoring, scaling as well as improving the hosting infrastructure of both the company's Web and App components. Subsequently, I embarked on two very interesting and enriching excursions into iOS App Development (both with React Native and with Swift) before moving back to Linz in 2017. That's when I joined my current company Fredmansky, where I'm in charge of our DevOps infrastructure which focuses on the LEMP stack (Linux, NGINX, MySQL, PHP) hosted on Virtual Serves and managed by the Hetzner Cloud Console with considerable use of AWS S3. In addition to handling all things DevOps at Fredmansky, I was able to gain invaluable knowledge and insights into all aspects of Full Stack Development with a myriad of different projects for various clients, including (but not limited to) the relaunch of dynatrace.com in 2018.

Given my extensive and year-long knowledge in Full Stack Development and DevOps, I think I'm a great fit for the Dynatrace Marketing team. What's more, I've already had the opportunity and pleasure to work together with quite a few members of the Marketing team as part of the cooperation between Dynatrace and Fredmansky, and I'd thus be delighted to join the team full-time and showcase my abilities on a daily basis. I'm very much looking forward to hearing from you!

Yours truly, Martin Hellwagner

Curriculum Vitae (Page 1)

hellwagner.io martin.hellwagner@gmail.com +43 670 604 2089



Work experience

July 2006 | Klagenfurt, Austria

Intern

ADDIT DIENSTLEISTUNGEN GMBH & CO. KG Dispatch and installation of computer systems

July 2007 | Klagenfurt, Austria

Intern

ARGE IT

Preparation of a Computer Science workshop

July 2008 – March 2009 | Klagenfurt, Austria

Civil servant

DIAKONIE KÄRNTEN GMBH

Youth mentoring

July-August 2010 | Klagenfurt, Austria
 February-March 2011 | Klagenfurt, Austria
 February-March 2013 | Klagenfurt, Austria

Intern

BERLINGER SYSTEM ENGINEERING GMBH Java Development

May 2012 – August 2013 | Darmstadt, Germany

Student employee

MAKEMYMOSAIC GMBH

Web Design, Web Development

March-June 2013 | Linz, Austria

Student employee

JOHANNES KEPLER UNIVERSITY Correction of course exercises



About me

Date of birth

July 23, 1989

Place of birth

Linz, Austria

Nationality

Austrian

Address

Landstr. 58 4020 Linz Austria



Skills

Languages

German Mother tongue
English Level C1
French Level B2
Mandarin Chinese Level A2

Operating Systems

Curriculum Vitae (Page 2)

hellwagner.io martin.hellwagner@gmail.com +43 670 604 2089



Work experience

Skills

March-May 2014 | Berlin, Germany

Intern

NOTENGRAFIK GBR

Correction of music notations, various IT tasks

January-March 2016 | Berlin, Germany

Student employee

WHY DO BIRDS GMBH

Java Development

May 2016 – March 2017 | Berlin, Germany

Employee

UBERCHORD ENGINEERING GMBH

Full Stack Web Development

April-July 2017 | Berlin, Germany

Employee

LEARNFIELD GMBH

Frontend Web Development

September-December 2017 | Linz, Austria

Employee

POCKET LIFESTYLE IT-SOLUTIONS GMBH

iOS Development

December 2017 – now | Linz, Austria

Employee

FREDMANSKY GMBH

Full Stack Web Development, DevOps

Reference projects:

- https://www.bistum-passau.de
- https://www.flyrotax.com
- https://fredmansky.at
- https://www.karriere.at/blog
- https://www.karriere.at/hr
- https://www.karriere.at/presse

Software

Microsoft Office Eclipse, Netbeans ///////// Atom, VS Code, Sublime JIRA, Trello, Pivotal Tracker Confluence ///////// Git, Subversion, SVN ////////// Adobe Illustrator, Sketch //////// Finale, Sibelius ///////// Pure Data, Max/MSP //////// Ableton Live //////// Native Instruments Traktor ////////

Technologies

HTML	/////////
CSS (LESS, SASS, Tailwind)	/////////
JavaScript (ES6)	/////////
React, React Native	//////////
Vue.js	/////////
PHP	/////////
Laravel, Zend	/////////
Craft CMS, Wordpress	/////////
Node.js, NPM, Yarn	/////////
MySQL, MongoDB	/////////
Java	/////////
Swift, Objective-C	//////////
C, C++	////////
Matlab	/////////
Hetzer, AutoDNS	/////////
Buddy, Jenkins	/////////
Google Cloud, AWS	/////////

Curriculum Vitae (Page 3)

hellwagner.io martin.hellwagner@gmail.com +43 670 604 2089

Education

September 2000 – June 2008 | Klagenfurt, Austria

High School

BG/BRG MÖSSINGERSTRASSE (passed with excellent success)

April-June 2009 | Toronto, Canada

Language Course

INTERNATIONAL LANGUAGE SCHOOLS Cambridge Certificate, Level C1 (passed with excellent success)

October 2009 – July 2013 | Linz, Austria

Bachelor of Science

IOHANNES KEPI FR UNIVERSITY **Computer Science** (passed with excellent success)

September 2011 – June 2012 | Taipei, Taiwan

Bachelor of Science

NATIONAL TAIWAN UNIVERSITY Computer Science, Mandarin Chinese (Exchange year)

October 2013 - March 2016 | Berlin, Germany

Master of Science

TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF BERLIN Audio Communication and Technology (passed with very good success)

March-June 2015 | Stockholm, Sweden

Master of Science

KTH ROYAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Audio Communication and Technology (Exchange semester)



Certifications

Life Guard Certificate

2004

Microsoft Certified **Professional Diplom for** Windows Server

2006

DELF Certificat. Niveau B1 & Niveau B2

2007 & 2008

Cambridge Certificate, Level C1

2009

Driving License, Class A & B

2010 & 2008

Certificate of an Al online course by the **Stanford University**

2011



Other

Piano lessons (classical music) & music theory courses

1998 - 2009

Piano lessons (Jazz) & participation in a Big Band

2002 - 2009

Design and development of an iOS App

2013 - 2014